Guide to the Horatio M. Reynolds Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Horatio McLeod Reynolds Papers
1890-1926
MS 1048
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The largest part of the papers is made up of student notebooks on Greek philology and classical studies including two notebooks on lectures on Aristotle and Hesiod that Reynolds attended in Berlin in 1888. Included also are several Yale College grade books (1890) and correspondence with the American School of Classical Studies at Athens.
Reynolds, Horatio McLeod, 1857-1929
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale College Dean's office in 1945.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Horatio McLeod Reynolds reflect his career as a classicist. Included are notes on Aristotle and Hesiod taken during Reynolds' study at the University of Berlin; grade books for Greek classes which he taught at Yale College; correspondence, printed matter, and other papers received by him in his capacity as secretary of the Managing Committee of the American School of Classical Studies in Athens; several items stemming from his appointment as a councillor of the Connecticut Society of the Archaeological Institute of America; and eight undated notebooks and loose notes on Greek philology and classical studies. The materials are arranged in a single chronological sequence.
Biographical / Historical
Horatio McLeod Reynolds, B.A. 1880.
Born April 13, 1857, in Wakefield, N. H.
Died October 3, 1929, in New Haven, Conn.
Father, William Buzzell Reynolds (M.D. Dartmouth 1852), a physician in Lynn, Lawrence, and Cambridge, Mass., and Union (Wakefield) and Chocorua, N. H.; enlisted as Private in 2d Regiment, United States Sharpshooters, 1861; promoted to Second Sergeant; later Assistant Surgeon and Surgeon, 2d United States Sanitary Service, until 1865; son of Samuel and Hannah (Farnham) Reynolds, of Acton, Maine. Mother, Clara Ellen (Swasey) Reynolds; daughter of Charles and Eunice (Buck) Swasey, of Milton Mills, N. H.
Maine Central Institute. Attended Bates College 1876-78; entered Yale as a Junior 1878; Winthrop Prize Junior year; oration appointment Senior year and speaker at Commencement; member Psi Upsilon.
Did graduate work at Yale on Soldiers' Memorial Fellowship 1880-82; taught the classics at Park Institute, Rye, N. Y., 1882-83; tutor in Greek at Yale 1883-88; assistant professor 1888-1893; Talcott professor of the Greek language and literature from 1893 until his retirement 1922, when made professor emeritus; studied Greek at Leipzig University in summer of 1885 and spent five months at University of Berlin in 1888; secretary of managing committee of American School in Athens 1901-1921; vice-president of Connecticut Society of Archaeological Institute of America 1914-1920; honorary M.A. Yale 1896; member American Philosophical Association, American Philological Association, and The Church of Christ in Yale University.
Married April 4, 1904, in New Haven, Florence Maud, daughter of Winston John and Margarette Elford (Dean) Trowbridge, a niece of James J. Dean (B.A. 1845), a great-great-granddaughter of Daniel Trowbridge (B.A. 1725), sister of Winston J. Trowbridge, '79, Frank D. Trowbridge, '84, and Elford P. Trowbridge, '87 (died September 14, 1930), and sister-in-law of William K. Townsend, '71. No children.
Death due to angina pectoris. Buried in Grove Street Cemetery, New Haven. His wife survived him. By the terms of his will a bequest was made to Yale as a residuary legatee, to establish a fund to be known as the Maud Trowbridge Reynolds and Horatio McLeod Reynolds Fund, the income of which is to be used to for the purchase of books for the University Library, and to constitute an auxiliary fund for the promotion of classical studies.
(Taken from Yale University Obituary Record, 1928-1931, pp. 84-85).
Americans -- Germany; Classical education; Greek literature; Students; Classicists; Reynolds, Horatio McLeod, 1857-1929; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory
  - University of Berlin notebooks
    - Professor Vahlen's lectures on Aristotle's Poetics, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Professor Kirchhoff's lectures on Hesiod, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale College grade books, 1890, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American School of Classical Studies at Athens
    - Correspondence relating to updating the list of students, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Managing Committee: pamphlets and circulars relating to the termination of B. H. Hill as director of the school, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut Society of the Archaeological Institute of America: mailing to members of the Council, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks and notes on classical studies, undated (Box 1, Folder 7 - 11)